International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Umhey, Frederick F., Executive Secretary. Correspondence, 1934-1955 [bulk 1940-1950]. 5780/005.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Frederick F. Umhey, Executive Secretary. Correspondence
1934-1955 [bulk 1940-1950].
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Executive Secretary.
5780/005.
28 cubic feet
28 linear ft.
Correspondence
The Umhey Executive Secretary records consist primarily of organizational records, subject files, and correspondence dealing with union administrative matters.
3654746
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Robert E. Lazar
Date completed:
March 1976
EAD encoding:
Casey S. Westerman, July 9, 2002
Biographical / Historical
Frederick Umhey was born in New York City in 1895. Unlike most officials in the ILGWU, Umhey was never employed as a garment maker. He began working in the office of Morris Hillquit, the labor lawyer, while still a teenager, and remained there until Hillquit's death in 1933. The following year, ILGWU President David Dubinsky appointed Umhey to the newly-created post of Executive Secretary. In that role, he served as administrator for such ILGWU programs as the Union Health Center, Unity House, and the death benefit fund. He also served as secretary to all of the standing committees of the union's General Executive Board. Frederick Umhey died in office in 1955.
Scope and Contents
Much of the collection is made up of routine correspondence. There is, however, significant material documenting such ILGWU activities as the annual convention, Union Health Center, Unity House (the ILGWU resort), and Unity Broadcasting Corporation, which owned a number of radio stations across the country. In addition, the collection contains correspondence with government officials about labor situations in the garment industry during World War II, and information about health care, benefits, and pensions for workers. Some of Umhey's personal records are also included.
Significant individuals in the collection include Luigi Antonini, David Dubinsky, Morris Hillquit, and Meyer Perlstein. Among the notable organizations represented in the collection are the joint boards and local unions of the ILGWU, Labor League for Human Rights, Labor's League for Political Education, the Liberal Party of New York, the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, and the U.S. Department of Labor.
Arrangement
Series I. Executive Secretary correspondence.
Boxes 1-55
Series II. Personal correspondence.
Box 56
Clothing trade--United States.; Clothing workers--Medical care--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Labor unions--Officials and employees.; Labor union locals.; Survivors' benefits--United States.; Women's clothing industry--United States.; Workers' compensation--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects--United States.; Correspondence; Organization files; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-; Hillquit, Morris, 1869-1933.; Perlstein, Meyer, 1884-1958.; Umhey, Frederick F., 1895-1955.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Management.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Union Health Center.; Labor League for Human Rights.; Labor's League for Political Education.; Liberal Party of New York State.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.; United States. Department of Labor.; Unity Broadcasting Corporation.; Unity House.
3654746
- I. Executive Secretary correspondence.
  - American Federation of Labor
    - 1950-55. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1948-49. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Convention: 1952-54. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - New York State Federation of Labor: 1946-51., Includes Union resolutions to Convention. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Health Plans: 1952-54., Includes Umhey statement before the House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, Jan. 1954; correspondence with Committee members. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Health Plans: 1948-49., correspondence re American Medical Assoc. in cooperation with consumer cooperatives and labor groups to work out a program for medical care and services. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Questionnaires: 1944-55. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Labor Conference on International Affairs, Inc.: 1945., Includes by-laws. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annuities
    - The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.: 1938-51., correspondence (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.: 1938-51. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Equitable Assurance: 1941-46., Includes Antonini's Policy, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Reports and Form Letters: 1945-47. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Retirement Inquiries: 1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Statistical Tables and Employee Records (n.d.). (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous: c. 1938. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Applications, Employment: 1946-49. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Attorneys
    - D. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Jacob J. Edelman: 1934-47. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - F (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - G. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - G., Includes correspondence with Morris Glushien and other members of General Counsel office. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - G., Includes correspondence with Morris Glushien, 1947-50. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - H-I. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Jack Johannes: 1938-46. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - K. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Clif. Langsdale: 1938-43. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Morris Levin: 1943-48. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - L., Includes correspondence with Abe Levy, 1938-49. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Elias Lieberman: 1936-51. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Markewich and Null: 1933-44. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - George E. Roewer: 1943-48. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - George E. Roewer: 1936-51. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - S. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Emil Schlesinger: 1938-49, Includes correspondence with Abraham Schlesinger. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Harry Sherr (Los Angeles): 1933-44. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - David Sokol: 1945-51 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - T-Z. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Blood Bank, Union and American Red Cross: 1952-53. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bonds
    - Analysis of Portfolios: 1944-47 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Purchases, General Office: 1953-54. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Purchases: 1940-43, 1949-52. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Purchases, Joint Boards and Locals: 1945-51. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Purchases, Canada: 1940-50. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Purchases, Defense Bonds: 1951. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Inquiries re Payment: 1949-51. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Manufacturers Trust Co., Custodian Account: 1943-48. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Records (Canada): 1952-53. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 1937-50. Misc. correspondence (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cabled Moneys, foreign. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - California Sportswear and Dress Assoc., Inc.: July 25, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cancer Committees 1952-54., Correspondence and minutes of American Cancer Society (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Central High School of Needle Trades: 1944-50. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Central Trades and Labor Council: 1948-55, Includes greetings in the Labor Chronicle. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - City Center: 1951-55. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - City Center: 1952., correspondence re Laszlo Halasz incident. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations: 1954-55., correspondence with Commission members. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Committees
    - Attendance Records of Union Officers: 1948-49. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Attendance: 1939-43. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Attendance: 1937-38. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Members: 1934-47., (Standing Committees) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Beach Wear: 1938., Includes report. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Dress Survey Committee: 1943-46. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Committee for the Nation's Health, Inc.: 1950-54. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Comparative Schedules: 1942-49. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Consumers League of New York: 1951-52. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Constitution of Union: 1952-53., Includes inquiries. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU conventions
    - 1953., Call and credentials; constitutional amendments; minutes of Convention Arrangements Committee. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1953., Delegate list, entertainment, form letters, financial matters. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1953., Guests; Hotel Morrison. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1953., Appeals from Los Angeles. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1953., Plumbers Hall and misc. correspondence (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1953, Printed material. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 1953., GEB ratification for paid officers to remain in office past retirement age. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 1950., Hotel Ambassador; arrangements, badges and banners. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1950., Committees, constitutional amendments, constitutional revision. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 1950., Convention hall, delegates' list, correspondence with J.W.de R.-Quistgaard re D.D. portrait. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 1950., correspondence on entertainment, exhibits and form letters. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 1950., Misc. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 1950., correspondence re movies, photos, printed material. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 1950., Publicity, reports, resolutions. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1937. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cotroneo, Jennie: 1941-57., Re Esther Vitro and ILGW of the World, Inc. case. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Death Benefits
    - General matters, 1943-54., Includes correspondence re assessments, inquiries, eligibility. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - 1937-42. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Committee Rulings: 1938-54. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1937-50., Includes reports, minutes of meetings, research data. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Disability Benefits: 1949-55., Includes statement made by James Lipsig to N.Y. State Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor conditions, Dec. 1950. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Displaced Persons: 1949-50., Includes letters and releases from Citizens Committee on Displaced Persons. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Displaced Persons: 1947-48. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Donnelly Garment Co. vs ILGWU
    - Correspondence and general memoranda, 1937-48. (Box 8, Folder 6a-6b)
    - Correspondence with attorneys, Arranged alphabetically by correspondent (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Acheson firm, 1939-46. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Clif. Langsdale firm, 1937-54. (Box 9, Folder 2a-2c)
    - Correspondence with Frank B. Walsh, Attorney, April 1939-41. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Frank B. Walsh, 1937-March 1939. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Legal matters, 1947-50., Includes analysis of ten-year controversy. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Production data. 1930's. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings file. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Dubinsky, David.
    - 1951., correspondence re pictorial biography. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Party: Feb. 1952. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1934-49. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Region Retirement Fund: 1952-54., Includes rules and regulations, by-laws and related correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Economic Controls: 1951-53., Includes Research Department bulletins. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Education Committee
    - 1953-56., Includes minutes of meetings, reports. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 1950-52. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - 1945-49. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Educational Foundation for the Apparel Industry: 1949-52. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.: 1938, 1940., Financial records. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology: 1953-54. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - F.I.T.: 1951-52. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Finance Committee: 1951-55., Includes minutes, reports, organizational requests. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Finance Committee: 1945-50. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Financial Assistance: 1944-46. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Form letters
    - A-C. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - D-H. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - I-Z. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Freydberg, G.H.& E., Co. Strikes 1954. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - General Executive Board
    - 1953 (Sept.), Includes minutes, reports from GEB committees and related correspondence (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1952 (Mar., Sept.). (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1951 (Feb., Sept.). (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1950 (Aug.). (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1949 (June, Nov.). (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1948 (Jan., June, Dec.). (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1947 (Jan., April, Sept.) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 1946 (April, Sept.). (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1945 (Dec.). (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - 1945 (April). (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 1944 (May, Oct.). (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1943 (Nov.). (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1941 (Apr.). (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - General Office
    - 1944-50., Application for assessment reduction. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Building Service Employees International Union, Local 32J: 1946-54., Includes collective agreements. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Group Insurance. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Health Insurances 1950-54. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Office Employees International Union, Local 153: 1939-55., correspondence pertaining to negotiations for agreements. (Box 13, Folder 8a-8b)
    - 1948-53., Office Employees (misc.). (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Hughes-Brees Bill, unemployment Insurance: 1951. (Box 13, Folder 10a-10b)
  - Institute of Applied Arts and Sciences (N.Y.C. Community College):
    - July 1933-55., F.F.U., member, Board of Trustees. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Nov. 1951-May 1953. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1949-Oct. 1951. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Institutions and Hospitals: 1939-49. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - ILGWU Campaign Committees:
    - 1954., correspondence, James Lipsig reports, pursuant to Title III of the Federal Corrupt Practices Act of 1925, correspondence on campaign. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1952. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1949. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1944. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - ILGWU Departments
    - Auditing
      - 1935-50. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - 1935-50. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Education
      - 1954-55., Includes correspondence, reports, programs, publications, releases; Mark Starr ( (Director). (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - 1952-53. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - 1950-51. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Health and Welfare
      - Funds: 1947-54. (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - 1944-46. (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - 1952-54. (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - 1949-51. (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Death Benefits: 1945-48. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Justice; 1938-54., Includes correspondence, releases, reports relating to printing of publication. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Mailing: 1945-48. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Management-Engineering, 1943-53., Includes reports. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Political: 1952-54, Includes releases issued by dept. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Promotion (advertising): 1950-54. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Research
      - 1952-55. Includes reports. (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - 1948-51. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Housing, East River Housing Corporation
    - Financial matters. 1951-54. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Legal matters. 1952-55. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Subscriptions from locals for purchasing housing bonds. 1955. (Box 17, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Inquiries: 1948-54., Requests for information. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Ives Committee, Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Relations (Irving M. Ives, Chairman): Relations (Irving M. Ives, Chairman): 1938-46, correspondence, reports, releases, hearings, minutes of meetings. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Investments: 1953-55. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Joint Board, Boston: 1947-49., Boston Ladies' Garment Workers Center. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Joint Board, Boston: 1939-55., Includes correspondence with local managers in Boston. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Joint Board, Chicago: 1948-54., correspondence with Morris Bialis. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Joint Board, Chicago: 1940-47. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Joint Board, Cleveland: 1940-50. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Joint Board, Cloak Out-of-Town: 1954., Includes Dominic DiCalbo vs. ILGWU. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Joint Board, Eastern Out-of-Town: 1952-55. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Joint Board, Eastern out-of-town: 1951-52. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Harrisburg, Allentown and Easton Locals: 1954, Misc. correspondence (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Joint Board, Kansas City: 1940-54. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Joint Board, Los Angeles Cloak: 1944-50. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Joint Board, Los Angeles Dress: 1946-49. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Joint Board, Los Angeles: 1954., Legal matters (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Miami Joint Council: 1954-55. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Midwest Region: 1947-50. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Joint Board, Milwaukee (and affiliated locals): 1935-48. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Joint Board, Montreal: 1940-50. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Joint Board, New York Dress (and upstate locals): 1953-54. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Ohio-Kentucky Region (and local affiliates): 1950-54. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Coast Area: 1947-50., Includes correspondence with Louis Levy (Director). (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Joint Board, Philadelphia Cloak: 1935, 1939-54. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Joint Board, Philadelphia Dress: 1944-54. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Joint Board, San Antonio: 1936-40, 1944, 1948. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Joint Board, San Francisco: 1940-49. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Joint Board, Seattle: 1936-37, 1941-49. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Southeastern Region: 1950-54., Includes correspondence bet. John Martin and Louis Stulberg. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Southeastern Region: 1940-42, 1946-49. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Southwestern Region: 1949-54., correspondence with Meyer Perlstein. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Southwestern Region: 1946-48. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Joint Board, South Jersey: 1942-53. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Joint Board, St. Louis: 1940-49. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Joint Board, Toronto: 1940-53. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Joint Board, Twin Cities: 1938-54. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Upper South Department (Maryland-Virginia District and Baltimore): 1947-50. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Upper South Department; 1940-42, 1946. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Joint Board, Winnipeg: 1946-53. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Jurisdiction Committee: 1934-54., Includes reports to GEB, minutes. (Box 21, Folder 1a-1c)
  - Labor Decisions: 1935-42., Includes related correspondence (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Labor Department: 1935-46., Includes correspondence on unions requesting incorporation from N.Y. Department of Labor (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Labor League for Human Rights (United Nations Relief): 1943-47., Includes releases and bulletins. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Labor's League for Political Education: 1949-50., Includes releases. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Labor Stages 1934-37., Includes certificate of incorporation and by-laws. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Legal Matters: 1937, 1940, 1948-50. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Legislation, Fair Employment Practice Commission: 1945-47. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Liberal Party: 1950-51., Includes Party reports and releases. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Liberal Party: 1944-49. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Loans and Endorsements: 1936-54. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Local 10, N.Y.: 1954. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Local 21, N.J.: 1937-48. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Local 23, N.Y.: 1954. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Local 32, N.Y.: 1954. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Local 48, N.Y. (Italian Cloak, Suit, Skirt, and Reefer Makers Union): 1939-53., Includes correspondence with Edward Molisani. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Local 60, N.Y. 1936-54. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Local 62, N.Y. (Undergarment and Negligee Workers Union): 1938-52., Includes "Labor Problems" (radio talks) by Samuel Shore. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Local 64, N.Y.: 1939-53. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Local 66, N.Y. (Bonnaz and Hand Embroiderers, Truckers and Pleaters Union): 1936-53., Includes correspondence with Zachary L. Freedman (Manager). (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Local 70, Portland, Ore.: 1939, 1941, 1948-49. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Local 82, N.Y.: 1938-52. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Local 89 (Italian Dress and Waistmakers Union): 1948-54., Includes correspondence with Luigi Antonini and John Gelo. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Local 89: 1935-47. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Local 91, N.Y. (Children's Dress and Infants' Wear, Housedresses and Bathrobe Makers): 1940-51., correspondence with Harry Greenberg. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Local 91 1944-50., Correspondence: re Local 91 Realty Corporation (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Local 98, N.Y. (Ladies' Garment Clerks Union): 1936-53. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Local 102, N.Y.: 1934-53. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Local 105, N.Y. (Snow Suits, Ski Wear, Leggings and Infants Novelty Wear workers Union): 1948-53. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Local 105, N.Y.: 1948-51., correspondence, minutes of meetings and reports re Local 105's controversies with Local 91. (Box 24, Folder 1 -- 4)
  - Local 117, N.Y. (Cloak, Suit, Infants' and Children's Coat Operators and Sample Makers): 1941-54. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Local 121, N.Y.: 1939-41. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Local 124, N.Y.: 1945-50. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Local 132, N.Y. (Plastic, Moulders and Novelty Workers Union): 1934-50., Includes correspondence with Martin Feldman. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Local 142, N.Y. (Ladies' Neckwear Workers Union): 1936-53, correspondence with Joseph Tuvim; controversy bet. N.Y. Central Trades and Labor Council and Tuvim, 1949-50. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Local 145, N.J.: 1935-36, 1945-46. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Local 155, N.Y. (Knitgoods Workers Union): 1941-54., correspondence with Louis Nelson. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Local 177, N.Y.: 1941-53. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Local 178, Fall River, Mass.: 1936-40. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Local 190, Pa. (and other Pa. locals): 1936-50 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Local 266, Calif: 1943-50. (Box 25, Folder 3a)
  - Local 339, Fla.: 1946-49. (Box 25, Folder 3b)
  - Local Managers Meetings: 1936-54., Includes reports and minutes. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Local Jurisdictional Disputes: 1934-48. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Local Personnel: 1945., Includes names and addresses of officers and members of local executive boards. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Lurye, William: 1949-53., correspondence re case and trust fund (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Lurye, William: 1949-50., Re film. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - March of Dimes Campaign (Infantile Paralysis)
    - 1949-55 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Aug. 1951-54. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - 1948-51. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Cases. 1950-55. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - General. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Military Exemptions: 1948-54. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: 1936-55., Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - A. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - B - H (Box 26, Folder 5a-5b)
    - I (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - J-M (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - N (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - O-P (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - R-S (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - T-Z (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Montreal, Canada: 1940-43, 1955-56., Legal matters. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board: 1954., Includes reports and resolutions, 18th Annual Meeting. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - National Labor Record; 1954-55, Includes correspondence with District Attorney's office re publication. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - New York Board Meeting of GEB: 1935-46. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - New York School of Industrial and Labor Relations (Cornell University): 1948-51. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - New York State Commission on Medical Care: 1945., Includes correspondence and reports. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - New York State Federation of Labor: 1952-54., Includes resolutions introduced by Union delegates. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Northeast Department: 1938-53., Includes legal matters. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Personnel, Requests for Union Positions: 1952-56. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Plettl, Martin: 1950-55. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Postal Telegraphs 1935., Case involving disclosure of information. (Box 27, Folder 11)